# **Utku Binkanat**

#### **Utku Binkanat**

2217 Sixth Street, Ceres, California

408-597-2054 utkubinkanatt@gmail.com

## About Me

I recently graduated from San Jose State University. During my time at San Jose State, I was a part of the San Jose State Men's Water Polo team through 2018-2021 and gained experience through my internship with the school's football program. I think my sports career helped me with being more disciplined and more goal-oriented. It taught me how to work as a team player and helped me become a lot more efficient in the work I do. Being a foreign student helped me improve my adjustment skills and showed me the importance of planning ahead.

I have started my web development journey in May of 2023. Since then I have been enrolled in Full-Stack Engineer path in Codecademy and I have earned various certificates from different available sources such as Codecademy and Free Code Camp.

## **Experience**

## San Jose State University Student Union Inc./ Lifeguard

April 2019- May 2023, San Jose, Ca

#### San Jose State Athletics/ Nutrition Assistant

Internship, January 2022-June 2022, San Jose, Ca

During my internship with SJSU Athletics, I assessed the body composition of athletes, made educational dietary handouts, prepared meal plans for athletes and took inventory and worked with strength and conditioning coaches to achieve various goals with athletes.

#### Galatasaray SK/Waterpolo Player

May 2013- August 2018, Istanbul, Turkey

Education

## Istanbul Anatolian High School

2014-2018 Istanbul, Turkey

## San Jose State University/ B.S Nutritional Science

August 2018- May 2023, San Jose, Ca Current GPA: 2.83

\_

### **Certificates**

**HTML Course** 

via Codecademy

JavaScript Course

via Codecademy

Responsive Web Design

via Free Code Camp

**JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures** 

via Free Code Camp

**Intermediate CSS Course** 

via Codecademy

Intermediate JavaScript Course

via Codecademy